They were not as thrilled to learn that we wanted them to help us spy on the Japanese population.
他们不同意  我们希望通过他们   帮助我们监控日本公众
They said it was against their laws.
他们说这是违反法律的
Of course, we tapped the entire country anyway.
不过我们还是监控了他们整个国家
And we didn't stop there. Once we owned their communication systems
我们不会止步于此  一旦我们从物理设施层面
We started going after the physical infrastructure.
一旦我们从物理设施层面
We'd slipped these little sleeper programs into power grids, dams, hospitals.
我们把这个小休眠程序  植入了他们的电站  大坝  医院
the idea was if the day came when Japan was no longer an ally
目的是  如果万一日本不再是我们的盟友了
it'd be lights out.
就给他全部停电
And it wasn't just the Japanese. We were planting malware in Mexico,
不仅仅是日本  我们还计划黑掉  墨西哥
Germany, Brazil, Austria.
德国  巴西  澳大利亚
I mean, China I can understand. Or Russia or Iran. Venezuela, okay.
我是说中国…还可以理解  或者俄国  伊朗  委内瑞拉  都可以
But, Austria?
但是…澳大利亚
You're also being ordered to follow most world leaders and heads of industry.
还必须奉命监控大多数领导人和商业巨头
you're tracking trade deals, sex scandals, diplomatic cables
甚至贸易协定  性丑闻  外交电报
to give the U.S. an advantage in negotiations at the G8
以给美国在 G8 上创造优势谈判地位
or leverage over Brazilian oil companies.
或跟巴西石油公司以小博大
Or helping to oust some third world leader who's not playing ball.
甚至帮助一些第三世界领导人上位
And ultimately the truth sinks in that no matter what justification you're selling yourself
最终呢  事实上  无论怎样你不过是在玩火自焚
this is not about terrorism.
这跟恐怖主义没有关系
Terrorism is the excuse.
恐怖主义只是借口
This is about economic and social control.
这事实上是经济和社会控制
And the only thing you're really protecting is the supremacy of your government.
然后你唯一真正保护的  仅仅是你政府的霸权